The story that seduced the world is now the most controversial film of the year.
Scandal is a drama, history, romance film directed by Michael Caton-Jones.
An English bon-vivant osteopath is enchanted with a young
exotic dancer and invites her to live with him.
He serves as friend and mentor, and through his contacts and parties she and
her friend meet and date members of the Conservative Party.
Eventually a scandal occurs when her affair with the Minister of War goes
public, threatening their lifestyles and their freedom.
Stephen Ward, played by John Hurt.
Christine Keeler, played by Joanne Whalley.
Mandy Rice-Davies, played by Bridget Fonda.
John Profumo, played by Ian McKellen.
Lord Astor, played by Leslie Phillips.
Mariella Novotny, played by Britt Ekland.
Scandal is a 1989 British historical drama film,
directed by Michael Caton-Jones.
It is a fictionalised account of the Profumo affair that rocked the
government of British prime minister Harold Macmillan.
It stars Joanne Whalley as Christine Keeler and John Hurt as
Stephen Ward, personalities at the heart of the affair.
Scandal was screened in competition at the 1989 Cannes Film Festival.
Its theme song "Nothing Has Been Proved" was written and produced
by Pet Shop Boys and sung by Dusty Springfield.
The film explores themes of london, england, sex scandal,
based on true story, scandal, cabaret dancer.
The tone is emotional.